<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Amazon EMR Serverless 🔋</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/emr-serverless/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/emr-serverless/</guid><description>Amazon EMR Serverless What is Amazon EMR?
Amazon EMR is a cloud big data platform for running large-scale distributed data processing jobs, interactive SQL queries, and machine learning (ML) applications using open-source analytics frameworks such as Apache Spark, Apache Hive, and Presto. Understanding clusters and nodes A cluster is a collection of Amazon Elastic Compute Cloud (Amazon EC2) instances. Each instance in the cluster is called a node. Each node has a role within the cluster, referred to as the node type.</description></item><item><title>Discover insights for RDS using Amazon DevOps Guru 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/devops-guru-rds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/devops-guru-rds/</guid><description>What is DevOps Guru for RDS?
DevOps Guru for RDS is a new ML-powered capability empowering developers and DevOps engineers to quickly detect, diagnose, and remediate a wide variety of database-related issues on Amazon RDS.
When DevOps Guru for RDS detects a database-related issue (such as resource overutilization, or misbehavior of certain SQL queries), the service immediately notifies you and provides diagnostic information, details on the extent of the problem, and intelligent recommendations to quickly resolve the issue.</description></item><item><title>Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering Archive Instant Access tier 🎚️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-intelligent-tiering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-intelligent-tiering/</guid><description>Amazon S3 Intelligent-Tiering: Archive Instant Access tier What is Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)?
Amazon S3 is one of the main building blocks of AWS. It&amp;rsquo;s advertised as&amp;quot; infinitely scaling&amp;quot; storage. It&amp;rsquo;s widely popular and deserves its section S3 provides unlimited storage space and works on the pay-as-you-use model. Service rates get cheaper as the usage volume increases Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; (directories). S3 resources, e.</description></item><item><title>Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3) Glacier Instant Retrieval 🎚️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-glacier-instant-retrieval/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-glacier-instant-retrieval/</guid><description>Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3) Glacier Instant Retrieval What is Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)?
Amazon S3 is one of the main building blocks of AWS. It&amp;rsquo;s advertised as&amp;quot; infinitely scaling&amp;quot; storage. It&amp;rsquo;s widely popular and deserves its section S3 provides unlimited storage space and works on the pay-as-you-use model. Service rates get cheaper as the usage volume increases Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; (directories). S3 resources, e.</description></item><item><title>Tracking Alerts Amazon S3 Event Notifications with Amazon EventBridge🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-eventbridge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-eventbridge/</guid><description>Amazon S3 Event Notifications with Amazon EventBridge What is Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)?
Amazon S3 is one of the main building blocks of AWS. It&amp;rsquo;s advertised as&amp;quot; infinitely scaling&amp;quot; storage. It&amp;rsquo;s widely popular and deserves its section S3 provides unlimited storage space and works on the pay-as-you-use model. Service rates get cheaper as the usage volume increases Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; (directories). S3 resources, e.</description></item><item><title>Implement Custom Lenses for the AWS Well-Architected Tool 📝</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/custom-lens-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/custom-lens-war/</guid><description>Custom Lenses for the AWS Well-Architected Tool What is AWS Well-Architected?
The AWS Well-Architected Framework describes key concepts, design principles, and architectural best practices for designing and running workloads in the cloud.
AWS Well-Architected helps cloud architects build secure, high-performing, resilient, and efficient infrastructure for various applications and workloads.
Built around six pillars
Operational excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance efficiency, Cost optimization, and Sustainability AWS Well-Architected provides a consistent approach for customers and partners to evaluate architectures and implement scalable designs.</description></item><item><title>Build Amazon Container Image using AWS EC2 Image Builder ⚒️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-image-builder-pipeline-container/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-image-builder-pipeline-container/</guid><description>Container Image pipeline using AWS EC2 Image Builder Introduction
EC2 Image Builder is a wholly managed AWS service that simplifies the process to automate the creation, management, and deployment of tailored, secure, and up-to-date server images that are pre-installed and pre-configured with software and settings to match specific IT standards.
Features of EC2 Image Builder
Greater productivity and reduced operations for building compliant and up-to-date images The more excellent service uptime Improved the security standard for deployments Centralized enforcement and lineage tracking Simplified sharing of resources across AWS accounts How EC2 Image Builder works?</description></item><item><title>Build Amazon Ec2 Image using AWS EC2 Image Builder ⚒️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-image-builder-pipeline-ec2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-image-builder-pipeline-ec2/</guid><description>Ec2 Image pipeline using AWS EC2 Image Builder Introduction
EC2 Image Builder is a wholly managed AWS service that simplifies the process to automate the creation, management, and deployment of tailored, secure, and up-to-date server images that are pre-installed and pre-configured with software and settings to match specific IT standards.
Features of EC2 Image Builder
Greater productivity and reduced operations for building compliant and up-to-date images The more excellent service uptime Improved the security standard for deployments Centralized enforcement and lineage tracking Simplified sharing of resources across AWS accounts How EC2 Image Builder works?</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Amazon Layered Virtual Private Cloud Architecture 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-layered-vpc-architecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Aug 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-layered-vpc-architecture/</guid><description>Introduction to Amazon Layered Virtual Private Cloud Architecture 1. Overview
This blog describes the basic Seven Layered network architecture. The following diagram shows the various components of the architecture; the VPC with two availability zones with several AWS Services, each of which is in place to support the organization within AWS Cloud. Each service has a high-level description in the sections below that provides an overview of that particular component. 2.</description></item><item><title>Exploring video transcoding on AWS using AWS Elemental Mediaconvert 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elemental-mediaconvert/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elemental-mediaconvert/</guid><description>AWS Elemental Mediaconvert Introduction
AWS Elemental MediaConvert is a file-based video transcoding service with broadcast-grade functionality. It offers to easily generate on-demand video (VOD) content for transmitting and multiscreen distribution at a larger scale.
The service merges advanced video and audio functionality via a UI with pay-as-you-go pricing. This service also allows for delivering compelling media experiences without having to worry about the criticality of building and operating your own video processing infrastructure.</description></item><item><title>Exploring AWS Workflow Studio💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/introduction-aws-workflow-studio/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/introduction-aws-workflow-studio/</guid><description>AWS Step Function Introduction
What is Step Function?
AWS Step Function is a serverless orchestration service that allows integrating multiple AWS services to collate &amp;amp; design an enterprise-critical application or workflow with advance conditional branching and error handling
Step Functions provides sequencing, error handling, retry logic, state, and offers a visualization-driven method to organize and represent the series of event-driven steps of your application through its graphical console.
And makes it easier and simpler to build and execute multiple-state event-driven critical applications.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Drift detection in AWS Cloudformation 🚀</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-drift-detection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-drift-detection/</guid><description>Drift detection Introduction
Drift detection allows to identify either a stack&amp;rsquo;s actual configuration differs or has drifted, from its original deployed values. We can use CloudFormation to identify drift on an entire stack or resources within the stack
A resource is examined as drifted if its actual property values delta from the expected property values. This contains if the property or resource has been modified or deleted. A stack is considered to have drifted if one or more of its resources have drifted</description></item><item><title>Catalog Data using AWS Glue Data Catalog 📖</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-glue-data-catalog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-glue-data-catalog/</guid><description>Introduction Glue Data Catalog is an AWS native service that allows persisting, tag, and extends metadata in a similar fashion like an Apache Hive metastore. Every AWS account holds one AWS Glue Data Catalog in every region.
It offers a consistent store where multiple sources can persist and lookup metadata to organize the data and leverage it to query and transform the data.
Following are the additional extensions to Glue Data Catalog:</description></item><item><title>Let's explore the working of AWS Application Migration Service 📦</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-application-migration-service/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-application-migration-service/</guid><description>AWS Application Migration Service Introduction
AWS Application Migration Service allows migrating the critical workloads to AWS avoiding any interference, or data leakage. With continuous block-level replication, automated machine conversion, and application stack orchestration, Application Migration Service simplifies the migration process and minimizes the chance for human error.
Whether we are moving to AWS or across regions within AWS, Application Migration Service simplicity the needs and provides the security measures require to win in today’s fast-paced digital era</description></item><item><title>Build metrics on logs with AWS Cloudwatch Metrics 📊</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-cloudwatch-metrics/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-cloudwatch-metrics/</guid><description>AWS Cloudwatch Metrics Introduction
Metrics are information around the performance of the systems.
Out of the box a few AWS services offer metrics at no cost for resources such as Ec2, EBS, and RDS. We can also switch to detailed monitoring for a couple of resources such as Ec2 to fetch more details around the performances, and the best thing is we can publish our own application metrics.
Amazon CloudWatch ingests all the metrics in the AWS account (both AWS resource metrics and application metrics) for searching, graphing, and alarms.</description></item><item><title>Exploring AWS App Runner 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-app-runner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-app-runner/</guid><description>Introduction of AWS App Runner Introduction
AWS App Runner is a service that offers a fast, simple, and cost-effective method to deploy a Github repository or a docker image as a web application in the AWS Cloud, and offers direct integration and delivery pipeline with fully managed operations, high performance, scalability, and security.
Out of the box, App Runner is built for the desired scale, so there is no requirement to re-platform or re-architect as the business grows and makes it simpler to rapidly deliver innovative solutions and business value, regardless of the language they are written in, even for teams that lack prior experience deploying and managing containers or infrastructure</description></item><item><title>Exploring Amazon Pinpoint💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-amazon-pinpoint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-amazon-pinpoint/</guid><description>Amazon Pinpoint Introduction
Amazon Pinpoint is an AWS service which allow to occupy the customers across multiple messaging channels. We can leverage Amazon Pinpoint to send push notifications, emails, SMS text messages, and voice messages.
Amazon Pinpoint allows to send customer oriented messages with better experiences which strengths the association with the customers and reduce the agitate.
Amazon Pinpoint provides functionalities such as:
Marketing campaigns and journeys
Transactional messages
Analytics tools</description></item><item><title>Let's understand the tips to secure Amazon S3 buckets 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/security-of-aws-s3/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/security-of-aws-s3/</guid><description>AWS S3 Security Introduction
Amazon S3 provides an optimal foundation because of its virtually unlimited scalability. You can seamlessly and non-disruptively increase storage from gigabytes to petabytes of content, paying only for what you use. Amazon S3 is designed to provide 99.999999999% durability.
It has scalable performance, ease-of-use features, and native encryption and access control capabilities. Amazon S3 integrates with a broad portfolio of AWS and third-party ISV data processing tools.</description></item><item><title>Configure AWS Managed Service For Grafana 📉</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-managed-grafana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-managed-grafana/</guid><description>AWS Managed Service For Grafana Introduction
Amazon Managed Service for Grafana (AMG) is a completely managed service that allows defining query, relations, and depicts trends, logs, and traces for the applications from various sources like Amazon CloudWatch, Amazon Elasticsearch Service, Amazon Timestream, AWS IoT SiteWise, AWS X-Ray, and Amazon Managed Service for Prometheus (AMP) and provides plug-ins to popular open-source databases, third-party ISV monitoring tools, as well as other cloud services.</description></item><item><title>How to configure AWS SSO? 🔐</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/enable-aws-sso/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/enable-aws-sso/</guid><description>Enable AWS SSO Introduction
Access management across different AWS accounts is a complicated and painful task but now with AWS SSO, it is much easier and simple to handle such activities. In this tutorial, we will focus on configuring AWS SSO to simplify user management across multiple accounts based on their roles.
This tutorial is divided into sections
Switch AWS SSO for your organization Configure AWS SSO permission sets Configure AWS SSO groups Allocate groups to your accounts Customize your SSO endpoint Connect to the AWS Console using your SSO endpoint Tutorial</description></item><item><title>What is AWS Parameter Store? 🔑</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-parameter-store/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-parameter-store/</guid><description>AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store Introduction
AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store offers secure, hierarchical storage for configuration data management and secrets management. You can persist in things such as passwords, connection strings, Ec2 AMI IDs, and license as parameter values. Values can be persisted as plain text or encrypted data. You can refer to parameters in your scripts by providing the unique name that you mention while creating the parameter. How can Parameter Store benefit my organization?</description></item><item><title>Deep-dive of custom resources in AWS Cloudformation 📌</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-custom-resources/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-custom-resources/</guid><description>Cloudformation Custom resources What is AWS Cloudformation?
AWS CloudFormation offers an easy way to deploy a collection of related AWS and third-party resources, provision them faster, and manage them throughout their lifecycles, by treating infrastructure as code.
A CloudFormation template contains information for the desired resources and their dependencies so we can launch and configure them together as a stack. We can use templates to create, update, and delete an entire stack as a single unit, instead of managing resources individually.</description></item><item><title>Exploring AWS Application Discovery Service 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-application-discovery-service/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-application-discovery-service/</guid><description>AWS Application Discovery Service Introduction
AWS Discovery Agent is an AWS software that is deployed in any targeted servers like physical on-premises servers, Amazon EC2 instances, and virtual machines for discovery and migration. It captures information like system configuration, system performance, running processes, and details of the network connections between systems.
This agent required root privileges to collect the information. When you start the Discovery Agent, it registers with the Application Discovery Service endpoint, arsenal.</description></item><item><title>Tracking Alerts with Amazon EventBridge in a real-time way 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/alerting-with-eventbridge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/alerting-with-eventbridge/</guid><description>Alerts with Amazon EventBridge Introduction
EventBridge bridges your application based on events. You can plug your own AWS platform with REST API, any SaaS applications, and custom apps as event sources that publish events to an event bus. You can state a filtering rule to refine events and target events to different services and REST endpoint destinations. EventBridge reduces the process of constructing an event-driven platform. EventBridge, decouple the destination from the source of the event, and this way you can refine and notify directly to EventBridge.</description></item><item><title>Query Insights from AWS CloudTrail Logs with AWS Athena 🔎</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrating-cloudtrail-logs-with-athena/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/integrating-cloudtrail-logs-with-athena/</guid><description>Fetch Insights from AWS CloudTrail Logs with Athena Introduction
Leveraging AWS Athena with CloudTrail logs is an impactful method to refine your insights of AWS service activity. For example, you can leverage queries to detect findings and further trace activity by attributes, like source IP address or user etc
Below are the steps we need to follow to implement this tutorial
Configure S3 bucket
Navigate to S3 console
Select Create bucket button</description></item><item><title>Generate Inventory of AWS resources using AWS Systems Manager 📝</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-inventory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-inventory/</guid><description>AWS Systems Manager Inventory Introduction
AWS Systems Manager Inventory offers transparency to your Amazon EC2 and on-premises processing ecosystem. We can leverage Inventory to capture metadata from your managed instances Metadata generated from AWS Systems Manager Inventory can be persisted in an Amazon Simple Storage Service (Amazon S3) bucket and post you can query the data and identify the version of the software and different configuration deployed in your instance as per your organization software policy, and which instances need to be updated You can configure Inventory on all of your managed instances by a single-click process.</description></item><item><title>What is AWS Budget &amp; Report?💰</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-budget-and-report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-budget-and-report/</guid><description>AWS Budget Monthly cost budget
Introduction
AWS Budgets provides a feature to handle cost and utilization by providing notifications when cost or usage is beyond the configured threshold. It can only be used as a mechanism to notify the usage and not a medium to restrict the actions. Budgets and notifications are directly dependent on your billing data and it is updated at least once a day NOTE: You may not receive an alarm for a forecasted budget if your account is new.</description></item><item><title>Tool to assist AWS Well-Architected Framework ⌛</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</guid><description>WALKTHROUGH OF THE WELL-ARCHITECTED TOOL Introduction
AWS Well-Architected Framework assists architects to create secure, scalable, durable, and efficient workload and it consists of five foundational pillars Operational Excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance Efficiency, and Cost Optimization It is a repeatable framework that assists customers and partners to validate the architectures and design that can scale over time. The AWS WA Tool, which is free at no cost and available under AWS Management Console, provides a way to regularly validate your workloads, discover potential issues, and capture your improvements.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy Grafana on Amazon Ec2? 🚀</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/deploy-grafana-ec2/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/deploy-grafana-ec2/</guid><description>Deploy Grafana Introduction Grafana is open-source software famous for creating graphs and visualizations for end-users to articulate the time-series data. In this tutorial, we will focus on the following steps and it will carry out on an EC2 Instance with Amazon Linux 2 as the operating system
Provisioning Ec2 server Installation of Grafana Testing the setup Adding Data Source in the Grafana Testing CloudWatch as a Data Source Step 1 - Provisioning Ec2 server</description></item><item><title>Unboxing Tips for AWS security 🛡️</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/security-best-practice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/security-best-practice/</guid><description>Ten AWS security tips
If you’re looking to improve your cloud security, an excellent place to start is to follow the top 10 most important cloud security tips that Stephen Schmidt, Chief Information Security Officer for AWS, laid out at AWS re:Invent 2019. Underneath represent the tips, expanded to aid you to take action.
Account information
Configure right contact info under AWS console management including the email address used to set up the account and those listed under Alternate Contacts.</description></item><item><title>Enable In-memory search using Amazon ElasticSearch Service 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elasticsearch-service-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elasticsearch-service-introduction/</guid><description>AWS ElasticSearch Service This article provides guidance on setting up an Elasticsearch cluster with Kibana on AWS (Amazon Web Services) cloud platform using CloudFormation. Also, it provides the user with instructions on how to access the cluster and Kibana endpoints.
Need for Elasticsearch and Use Cases
Elasticsearch is a managed AWS (Amazon Web Services) service for Log analytics and management. A common use case is Monitoring Infrastructure or Application Performance and assisting in failure diagnosis.</description></item><item><title>How to achieve message Filtering in Amazon SNS? 📨</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-sns-filtering/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-sns-filtering/</guid><description>MESSAGE FILTERING What is Amazon SNS Message Filtering?
By default, an Amazon SNS topic subscriber receives every message published to the topic. To receive a subset of the messages, a subscriber must assign a filter policy to the topic subscription. A filter policy is a simple JSON object containing attributes that define which messages the subscriber receives.
When you publish a message to a topic, Amazon SNS compares the message attributes to the attributes in the filter policy for each of the topic’s subscriptions.</description></item><item><title>Explore managed Kubernetes offering from AWS (AWS EKS)🚀</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-eks-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-eks-introduction/</guid><description>Introduction to Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service What is Amazon EKS?
Amazon EKS (Elastic Container Service for Kubernetes) is a managed Kubernetes service that allows you to run Kubernetes on AWS without the hassle of managing the Kubernetes control plane. The Kubernetes control plane plays a crucial role in a Kubernetes deployment as it is responsible for how Kubernetes communicates with your cluster The big benefit of EKS, and other similar hosted Kubernetes services, is taking away the operational burden involved in running this control plane.</description></item><item><title>How to deploy scheduled task in AWS Fargate? ⏰</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/scheduled-task-aws-fargate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/scheduled-task-aws-fargate/</guid><description>Create a scheduled task in AWS Fargate AWS Fargate
Fargate is a managed service for container orchestration provided by AWS. In ECS, we always need to provision the EC2 cluster first before running services. Also, there is an operating cost to maintain the cluster. When there is a change, we need to change both the underlying cluster (the number of EC2 instances) and services (the number of tasks). In Fargate, you don’t need to operate the cluster.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/redshift-serverless/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/redshift-serverless/</guid><description>AWS Redshift Serverless</description></item><item><title/><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/readme/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/readme/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>