<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloudformation on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/cloudformation/</link><description>Recent content in cloudformation on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/cloudformation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Understanding Drift detection in AWS Cloudformation 🚀</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-drift-detection/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-drift-detection/</guid><description>Drift detection Introduction
Drift detection allows to identify either a stack&amp;rsquo;s actual configuration differs or has drifted, from its original deployed values. We can use CloudFormation to identify drift on an entire stack or resources within the stack
A resource is examined as drifted if its actual property values delta from the expected property values. This contains if the property or resource has been modified or deleted. A stack is considered to have drifted if one or more of its resources have drifted</description></item><item><title>Deep-dive of custom resources in AWS Cloudformation 📌</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-custom-resources/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/cloudformation-custom-resources/</guid><description>Cloudformation Custom resources What is AWS Cloudformation?
AWS CloudFormation offers an easy way to deploy a collection of related AWS and third-party resources, provision them faster, and manage them throughout their lifecycles, by treating infrastructure as code.
A CloudFormation template contains information for the desired resources and their dependencies so we can launch and configure them together as a stack. We can use templates to create, update, and delete an entire stack as a single unit, instead of managing resources individually.</description></item></channel></rss>