<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>eventbridge on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/eventbridge/</link><description>Recent content in eventbridge on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/eventbridge/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tracking Alerts Amazon S3 Event Notifications with Amazon EventBridge🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-eventbridge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/s3-eventbridge/</guid><description>Amazon S3 Event Notifications with Amazon EventBridge What is Amazon Simple Storage Service (S3)?
Amazon S3 is one of the main building blocks of AWS. It&amp;rsquo;s advertised as&amp;quot; infinitely scaling&amp;quot; storage. It&amp;rsquo;s widely popular and deserves its section S3 provides unlimited storage space and works on the pay-as-you-use model. Service rates get cheaper as the usage volume increases Amazon S3 allows people to store objects (files) in &amp;ldquo;buckets&amp;rdquo; (directories). S3 resources, e.</description></item><item><title>Tracking Alerts with Amazon EventBridge in a real-time way 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/alerting-with-eventbridge/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/alerting-with-eventbridge/</guid><description>Alerts with Amazon EventBridge Introduction
EventBridge bridges your application based on events. You can plug your own AWS platform with REST API, any SaaS applications, and custom apps as event sources that publish events to an event bus. You can state a filtering rule to refine events and target events to different services and REST endpoint destinations. EventBridge reduces the process of constructing an event-driven platform. EventBridge, decouple the destination from the source of the event, and this way you can refine and notify directly to EventBridge.</description></item></channel></rss>