<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>introduction on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/introduction/</link><description>Recent content in introduction on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Exploring AWS App Runner 💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-app-runner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-app-runner/</guid><description>Introduction of AWS App Runner Introduction
AWS App Runner is a service that offers a fast, simple, and cost-effective method to deploy a Github repository or a docker image as a web application in the AWS Cloud, and offers direct integration and delivery pipeline with fully managed operations, high performance, scalability, and security.
Out of the box, App Runner is built for the desired scale, so there is no requirement to re-platform or re-architect as the business grows and makes it simpler to rapidly deliver innovative solutions and business value, regardless of the language they are written in, even for teams that lack prior experience deploying and managing containers or infrastructure</description></item><item><title>What is AWS Budget &amp; Report?💰</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-budget-and-report/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-budget-and-report/</guid><description>AWS Budget Monthly cost budget
Introduction
AWS Budgets provides a feature to handle cost and utilization by providing notifications when cost or usage is beyond the configured threshold. It can only be used as a mechanism to notify the usage and not a medium to restrict the actions. Budgets and notifications are directly dependent on your billing data and it is updated at least once a day NOTE: You may not receive an alarm for a forecasted budget if your account is new.</description></item><item><title>Enable In-memory search using Amazon ElasticSearch Service 🔍</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elasticsearch-service-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-elasticsearch-service-introduction/</guid><description>AWS ElasticSearch Service This article provides guidance on setting up an Elasticsearch cluster with Kibana on AWS (Amazon Web Services) cloud platform using CloudFormation. Also, it provides the user with instructions on how to access the cluster and Kibana endpoints.
Need for Elasticsearch and Use Cases
Elasticsearch is a managed AWS (Amazon Web Services) service for Log analytics and management. A common use case is Monitoring Infrastructure or Application Performance and assisting in failure diagnosis.</description></item><item><title>Explore managed Kubernetes offering from AWS (AWS EKS)🚀</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-eks-introduction/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/aws-eks-introduction/</guid><description>Introduction to Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service What is Amazon EKS?
Amazon EKS (Elastic Container Service for Kubernetes) is a managed Kubernetes service that allows you to run Kubernetes on AWS without the hassle of managing the Kubernetes control plane. The Kubernetes control plane plays a crucial role in a Kubernetes deployment as it is responsible for how Kubernetes communicates with your cluster The big benefit of EKS, and other similar hosted Kubernetes services, is taking away the operational burden involved in running this control plane.</description></item></channel></rss>