<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>overview on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/overview/</link><description>Recent content in overview on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/overview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Let's explore the working of AWS Application Migration Service 📦</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-application-migration-service/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 May 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-application-migration-service/</guid><description>AWS Application Migration Service Introduction
AWS Application Migration Service allows migrating the critical workloads to AWS avoiding any interference, or data leakage. With continuous block-level replication, automated machine conversion, and application stack orchestration, Application Migration Service simplifies the migration process and minimizes the chance for human error.
Whether we are moving to AWS or across regions within AWS, Application Migration Service simplicity the needs and provides the security measures require to win in today’s fast-paced digital era</description></item><item><title>Exploring Amazon Pinpoint💡</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-amazon-pinpoint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Apr 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-amazon-pinpoint/</guid><description>Amazon Pinpoint Introduction
Amazon Pinpoint is an AWS service which allow to occupy the customers across multiple messaging channels. We can leverage Amazon Pinpoint to send push notifications, emails, SMS text messages, and voice messages.
Amazon Pinpoint allows to send customer oriented messages with better experiences which strengths the association with the customers and reduce the agitate.
Amazon Pinpoint provides functionalities such as:
Marketing campaigns and journeys
Transactional messages
Analytics tools</description></item><item><title>Configure AWS Managed Service For Grafana 📉</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-managed-grafana/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-managed-grafana/</guid><description>AWS Managed Service For Grafana Introduction
Amazon Managed Service for Grafana (AMG) is a completely managed service that allows defining query, relations, and depicts trends, logs, and traces for the applications from various sources like Amazon CloudWatch, Amazon Elasticsearch Service, Amazon Timestream, AWS IoT SiteWise, AWS X-Ray, and Amazon Managed Service for Prometheus (AMP) and provides plug-ins to popular open-source databases, third-party ISV monitoring tools, as well as other cloud services.</description></item><item><title>What is AWS Parameter Store? 🔑</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-parameter-store/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/overview-of-aws-parameter-store/</guid><description>AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store Introduction
AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store offers secure, hierarchical storage for configuration data management and secrets management. You can persist in things such as passwords, connection strings, Ec2 AMI IDs, and license as parameter values. Values can be persisted as plain text or encrypted data. You can refer to parameters in your scripts by providing the unique name that you mention while creating the parameter. How can Parameter Store benefit my organization?</description></item><item><title>Tool to assist AWS Well-Architected Framework ⌛</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</guid><description>WALKTHROUGH OF THE WELL-ARCHITECTED TOOL Introduction
AWS Well-Architected Framework assists architects to create secure, scalable, durable, and efficient workload and it consists of five foundational pillars Operational Excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance Efficiency, and Cost Optimization It is a repeatable framework that assists customers and partners to validate the architectures and design that can scale over time. The AWS WA Tool, which is free at no cost and available under AWS Management Console, provides a way to regularly validate your workloads, discover potential issues, and capture your improvements.</description></item></channel></rss>