<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>war on Sanchit's blog</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/war/</link><description>Recent content in war on Sanchit's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/tags/war/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Implement Custom Lenses for the AWS Well-Architected Tool 📝</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/custom-lens-war/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/custom-lens-war/</guid><description>Custom Lenses for the AWS Well-Architected Tool What is AWS Well-Architected?
The AWS Well-Architected Framework describes key concepts, design principles, and architectural best practices for designing and running workloads in the cloud.
AWS Well-Architected helps cloud architects build secure, high-performing, resilient, and efficient infrastructure for various applications and workloads.
Built around six pillars
Operational excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance efficiency, Cost optimization, and Sustainability AWS Well-Architected provides a consistent approach for customers and partners to evaluate architectures and implement scalable designs.</description></item><item><title>Tool to assist AWS Well-Architected Framework ⌛</title><link>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sanchitdilipjain.github.io/post/walkthrough-of-war-tool/</guid><description>WALKTHROUGH OF THE WELL-ARCHITECTED TOOL Introduction
AWS Well-Architected Framework assists architects to create secure, scalable, durable, and efficient workload and it consists of five foundational pillars Operational Excellence, Security, Reliability, Performance Efficiency, and Cost Optimization It is a repeatable framework that assists customers and partners to validate the architectures and design that can scale over time. The AWS WA Tool, which is free at no cost and available under AWS Management Console, provides a way to regularly validate your workloads, discover potential issues, and capture your improvements.</description></item></channel></rss>